因此，当参加浓缩物课程的第18讲时，以及
so when out to the 18th lecture of the
condensed matter course and and over the
最近几周，我们一直在积累有关
last couple weeks
we've been building up our knowledge of
如何了解固体中的电子我们知道关于能带结构的知识
how to understand electrons in solids we
know about band structure we know of
我们知道的电子和空穴就像有效物质一样，我们知道关于掺杂
electrons and holes we know about like
effective masses we know about doping
在这一点上，我们实际上已经获得了足够的知识，我们可以
and at this point we actually have
arrived at enough knowledge that we can
实际考虑将材料组合在一起以制造真实的设备
actually think about putting together
materials in order to make real devices
尤其是半导体器件
and in particular semiconductor devices
semiconductor devices which is in some
凝聚态物理整个领域的最高荣耀是
way the the crowning glory of the entire
field of condensed matter physics it's
因为我们可以制造半导体设备，例如
because we can make semiconductor
devices that we can build things like
我们可以制造手机的计算机，我们可以制造iPad以及其他所有这些
computers we can build cell phones we
can build iPads and and all these other
我们认为理所当然的事情，并且完全改变了我们您所知道的方式
things that we take for granted and
completely change our you know the way
这几天我们活着都是因为我们了解半导体物理学
we live these days it's all because we
understand semiconductor physics
很好的消息是，这完全不是可检查的，但是
extremely well the good news is that
it's totally not examinable but that
意味着我们不能坏消息是意味着我们不能花费很多时间
means that we can't the bad news is that
means we can't spend a whole lot of time
即使这是一个非常有趣的主题，您也可以花费
on it even though it's extremely
interesting subject you could spend you
知道您一生的剩余时间来研究半导体器件，并且
know the rest of your entire life
studying semiconductor devices and
建立新的，也许有人在这个房间里真的会
building new ones and probably some
people in this room really will the the
半导体行业是一个巨大的行业，拥有许多
semiconductor industry is a huge
industry that employs many many
物理学家，所以人们会思考
physicists so people will be thinking
about semiconductor devices in the
未来，我保证你会有人，但对我们来说，它将限于40
future I promise you someone will but
for us it's gonna be limited to about 40
分钟，但我们将看到40分钟内可以到达的距离
minutes but we'll see how far we can get
in 40 minutes
所以我们要讨论的最简单的半导体器件是量子
so the simplest semiconductor device
we're going to discuss is the quantum
好吧，无非就是一种材料夹在另一种材料中的三明治
well which is nothing more than a a
sandwich of one material inside another
材料，所以您想象这里有三层材料
material so you imagine having a three
layer material over here it's over here
我们将砷化铝放在这里是砷化镓，这里是铝
we'll put aluminum arsenide here is
gallium arsenide and here's aluminum
砷化物，所以在我们这面是砷化铝之间的薄层镓
arsenide so it's a thin layer gallium on
our side in between aluminum arsenide
这是X的一些位置坐标，我们实际上已经研究了这种材料
this is X some position coordinate and
we've actually studied this material
在砷化镓之前，记得它是具有锌混合结构的
before gallium arsenide and remember it
was a it has zinc blende structure it's
具有砷化铝基础的FCC就像砷化镓一样，除了
FCC with the basis aluminum arsenide is
just like gallium arsenide except you
用新的铝代替镓，所以也有FCC和基础
replace the gallium with a new aluminum
so it's also FCC with basis and the
选择这些材料的原因是我们的砷化铝镓
reason that chosen these these materials
aluminum arsenide gallium ours
实际上，这里有一点大自然的恩赐
is actually the there's a little bit of
a gift of nature here it turns out that
砷化镓和晶格常数的晶格常数
the lattice constant the size of the
unit cell for gallium arsenide and
砷化铝极其精确地相同
aluminum arsenide is extremely extremely
precisely the same it's just something
随机发生，使这些非常理想的材料可用于
that randomly occurs which makes these
very desirable materials to work with
使事情变得非常理想的原因是意味着您可以排队
the reason that makes things very
desirable is means that you can line up
直接位于砷化镓和砷化铝之间的原子，以及
the atoms directly between the gallium
arsenide and the aluminum arsenide and
基本上只有一个巨型水晶，当您穿过水晶时，
basically have just one giant crystal
and as you walk through the crystal the
唯一改变的是从这种材料到所有材料
only thing that changes is in going from
this material to this material all the
铝被镓秘密地取代了x'好，所以看起来就像一个
aluminum's get secretly replaced with
gallium x' ok so it just looks like one
一种材料的大晶体，但是在这里有铝
big crystal of one material but and over
here you have aluminum's here you have
镓新材料回到这里，铝又是
gallium xin the new back here and it's
aluminum's again the difference between
不同的材料是砷化铝中的带隙实际上是
the different materials is that the
bandgap in aluminum arsenide is actually
比砷化镓中的带隙大，所以您可能会有一个带
bigger than the bandgap in gallium
arsenide so you might have a band
像这样的结构这里是大带隙这里是小带隙
structure that looks like this it's big
band gap out here small band gap here
这里的带隙很大，所以如果我们绘制导带能量，则每次导通
big band gap here so if we plot the
conduction band energy each conduction
它会在这里很大，然后在这个区域掉落，这就是
it will be big here then it drops down
in this region here which is known as
量子阱，然后又回到这里，所以这是铝
the quantum well and then it comes back
up over here so this is the aluminum
砷化物这里是砷化镓这里是砷化铝
arsenide here's the gallium arsenide
here's the aluminum arsenide so if
你是一个生活在该导带中的电子，你所看到的是你
you're an electron living in that
conduction band what you see is you
基本上看到了某种约束力，例如
basically see a well some sort of
confining potential like a particle in
框，您将通常在框内的那个粒子中形成波动函数
box and you would form a wave function
in that particle in a box in the usual
当然，您也可以在其中激发状态波功能
way and of course you could have excited
state wave functions also in that
盒子里的颗粒也是这种和那种之间的唯一区别
particle in a box also the only
difference between this and the kind of
盒子中的粒子您在量子力学课程中解决的问题
particle in a box problems that you
solved in your quantum mechanics courses
就是如果M星不是M，则电子的有效质量为
is that if the M star not M the
effective mass of the electron is
重要的是，电子在导带中的有效质量是
important the effective mass of the
electron in the conduction band is the
缩短方程中显示的重要内容不是
important thing that shows up in the
shorteners equation not be real mass of
电子和其他不同的是X的V
the electron and the other thing that's
different is that this V of X this
电位实际上是由于带结构所致
potential is actually due to the band
structure due to band structure
这就是导致电位在底部上升和下降的原因
so that's what's causing the potential
to go up and down at the bottom of the
如果您考虑一下，导带现在正在上下移动
conduction band is moving is moving up
and down now if you think about the
价带，实际上看起来相反
valence band
it actually looks the opposite the
价带价价带的顶部从低开始，直到高
valence band valence the top of the
valence band starts low it was up high
在中间，然后像这样回落，如果你整个生活
in the middle and then comes back down
like this and if you are a whole living
在价带中，记住孔要向上爬
in the valence band
remember the holes try to go up instead
像电子一样下降的尝试试图下降，因此实际上可以得到一个空穴
of coming down like electrons try to
come down so in fact a hole can get
卡在这种颠倒的井中，它也将形成一个特殊的盒子
stuck in this sort of upside-down well
and it would also form a particular box
该量子阱内部的波函数，因此您可以将两个电子都俘获
wavefunction inside inside this quantum
well so you can trap both an electron up
在这里和这里的一个洞现在实际上已经非常使用了这种非常简单的结构
here and a hole down here now this very
simple structure is actually used quite
在半导体行业中经常用于制造
frequently in in the semiconductor
industry very frequently for making
激光会发生什么，你想象在这里放一个电子和一个洞
lasers what happens is you imagine
putting an electron up here and a hole
在这里，然后电子可以在发射光子的同时落入该孔
down here and then an electron can fall
into that hole while emitting a photon
结果出来了，如果您上学了一些激光物理学，就知道如何
it comes out and if you learn some laser
physics last term you understand how if
你有这样的过渡，你可以建立，你可以从中建立激光器
you have transitions like this you can
build you can build lasers out of them
关于这种结构整洁的是，您可以改变能量
the thing that's neat about this
structure is you can change the energy
通过改变孔的宽度来改变本征态
of the eigenstates by changing the width
of the well so if you make it a thinner
在砷化铝里面的砷化镓里面的一层
layer in inside this of gallium arsenide
inside aluminum arsenide then the the
能量本征态发生变化仅仅是因为能量本征态始终取决于
energy eigenstates change just because
the energy eigenstates always depend on
盒子的宽度，因此您可以通过以下方式调节即将发出的声子的能量
the width of the box and so you can tune
the energy of the outcoming phonon by
只是改变孔的宽度，这就是为什么这种设备
just changing the width of the well and
that's why this kind of device is
经常在光电子学中使用好吧，所以这是最简单的
frequently used in optoelectronics okay
all right so this is a very simplest
我们需要考虑的设备，我们不必担心任何掺杂剂
device that we ever need to think about
we don't have to worry about any dopants
现在我们要考虑添加掺杂剂，这将使我们能够
now we're going to think about adding
dopants which when it will enable us to
制造一些更复杂的设备，因此掺杂，尽管我在
make some much more complicated devices
so doping and although I said at the
讲座开始时不对半导体器件进行检查
beginning of the lecture the
semiconductor devices is not examinable
兴奋剂是可以检查的，我们将在上一堂课的最后讨论
doping is examinable we are we discussed
this at the end of last lecture I'll
提醒您一些结果，那么如果我们掺杂半导体，密度
remind you of some of the results then
if we dope a semiconductor the density
导带中的电子数是一些常数，我不会写下来
of electrons in the conduction band is
some constants which I won't write down
乘以一个指数因子，甚至是负βII传导负μ
times an exponential factor even the
minus beta II conduction minus mu
所以基本上这个指数的大部分告诉你
so basically the big part of this the
exponential factor tells you that you
必须激活电子从化学物质进入导带
have to activate an electron up into the
conduction band from the chemical
势，它以指数方式被激活到导带中，然后
potential it's exponentially activated
up into the conduction band okay and
然后前面有几个前置因素没那么有趣
then there's a couple pre factors out
front which aren't that interesting
同样，实际上应该清楚，当您提高化学势时
similarly and actually should be clear
that as you raise the chemical potential
朝向导带，导带中的电子密度
towards the conduction band the density
of electrons in the conduction band goes
如果我们想知道价带中空穴的密度，
up similarly if we want to know about
the density of holes in the valence band
P某些常数甚至会减去beta nu减去DV，所以类似
P that some constants also even minus
beta nu minus DV so similarly we have
孔被激活到价带，因为记住
the holes being activated down into the
valence band because remember to
需要能量将一个孔向下推到价带中
requires energy to push a hole down into
the valence band the holes want to
如果您将化学势向下移动，气泡会再次被激活
bubble up again it's activated if you
move the chemical potential down towards
价带，然后空穴的密度上升，质量定律
the valence band then the density of
holes goes up the law of mass action
群众行动告诉我们T的这两个事物n的乘积等于
mass action tells us that the product of
these two things n of T P of T equals
这两个常数中有两个常数，然后将此e传递给
and there's a couple of these these two
sets of constants then this e to the
负βe传导负价，这与化学反应无关
minus beta e conduction minus e valence
and this is independent of the chemical
势，所以应该从这些方程中拿走什么呢？
potential so what one should take away
from this these equations for which have
与电子密度和空穴的导带密度有关
to do with density of electrons and the
conduction band density of holes in the
价带是如果我们用
valence band
is that if we dope if dope heavily with
换句话说，如果有很多供体，则化学势会上升到
n in other words and a lot of donors
then chemical potential goes up up to
导带能量朝着导带能量上升
the conduction band energy goes up
towards the conduction band energy
因为我们必须增加电子数量同时将产品保留在这里
because we have to raise the number of
electrons while keeping the product here
固定，唯一发生的方法是提高化学势
fixed and the only way that happens is
by raising the chemical potential
同样地，如果我们大量地使用毒品
similarly if we dope heavily if dope
heavily
P受体在价带上增加空穴，然后mu下降到
with P acceptors adding holes to the
valence band then mu goes down to the
价带能量好很多，这就是可以检验的一切
valence band energy okay is that much
good that's everything that's examinable
关于设备物理的是这两个板块，所以现在我们可以做
about a device physics is these two two
boards right here so now what we can do
我们可以考虑如果在半导体中加入一些掺杂剂会发生什么
is we can think about what happens if we
put some dopants in our semiconductor
这将我们带到第一个有趣的设备PN
and this brings us to our first
interesting device which is the PN
结PN结被意外发现或本质上被发现
Junction PN Junction which was
surprisingly discovered or essentially
费迪南德·布劳恩·弗农·布朗（Ferdinand Braun Vernon Brown）在1874年发现的行星实际上不知道是什么
discovered in 1874 by Ferdinand Braun
Vernon Brown actually had no idea what
是他被发现的，但他是一个足够聪明的物理学家，以至于意识到
it was he discovered but he was a clever
enough a physicist to realize that what
他发现真的很有趣，实际上这变得非常重要
he discovered was really interesting in
fact it became an extremely important
事情是一个小的电子小部件，使开发
thing it was a little electronic widget
that enabled the development of the
没有勃拉姆斯发现这个设备的收音机，我们将无法
radio without Brahms discovering of this
device we wouldn't have been able to
建立收音机，当然，收音机是真正的发明之一
build a radio and of course the radio is
one of the inventions that really
PN结在许多方面改变了通信并改变了世界
changed communications and change the
world in many ways so PN Junction
改变了世界回到1800年代或1900年代初，但实际上
changed the world back in the 1800's or
beginning of 1900s but actually it
真的不明白为什么PN结表现出它的行为方式
wasn't really understood why the PN
Junction behaved the way it did in for
布朗发现后大约70年，让我们看看是否可以
about seventy years after Browns
discovery so let's see if we can
了解布朗不明白的是什么，所以首先
understand what it was that Brown didn't
understand so first of all what is the
结构，所以您从一大块半导体开始，而您只需掺杂一个
structure so you start with a big piece
of semiconductor and you just P dope one
当你梵天时，你要涂另一面，然后再涂另一面
side of it and you n dope the other side
and dope the other side now when Brahma
实际上建造了这个，他拿了两块材料，只是把它们粘住了
actually built this he took two pieces
of materials and just stuck them
在现代时代，您会一起取一个大晶体，然后添加一些掺杂剂
together in the modern era you take one
big crystal and you add some dopants
在这里，您可以在此处添加一些掺杂剂，而不是
over here and you add some dopants over
here much more controlled than what
布朗做到了，但总体上是相同的想法，所以让我们来画一下
brown did but generally the same idea
and so let's draw a picture of where the
导带和价带是，所以导带能量可能是
conduction band and the valence band are
so the conduction band energy might be
在这里价带能量可能在这里这里价带在这里和这里
up here the valence band energy might be
down here a valence down here and here's
我们中间的师现在在这边
our division in the middle now over on
this side
我们是n掺杂的，这意味着我们在传导中有一堆电子
we're n-doped so that means we have a
bunch of electrons up in the conduction
带在这里，化学势是方法
band
here and the chemical potential is way
在这里，在导电带附近，因为我们已经用
up here mu up here near the conduction
band because we've doped it with the
电子，所以化学势上升到导带能量
electron so the chemical potential went
up towards the conduction band energy
现在好了，在这里，价带上有一堆孔，
good now over down here we have a bunch
of holes in the valence band and the
到目前为止，化学势已被拉低至价带能附近
chemical potential has been pulled down
to near the valence band energy so far
很好，现在它的绘制方式
so good
alright now the way it's drawn this
看起来您左侧有负电荷，而在左侧有正电荷
looks like you have negative charges on
the left and positive charges on the
对，这实际上是不正确的，因为我们省略了原子核上的电荷
right that's not actually true because
we've left out the charges on the nuclei
所以原子核有电荷我们的原子核也有补偿
so the nuclei have charges also nuclei
nukes we and they have compensating
像这样的收费，而comping chain在这里收费，因为您还记得
charges like this and comping chain
charges over here because you remember
当您添加例如在硅中添加磷时，您会添加额外的
when you add a for example when you add
a phosphorous to silicon you add a extra
核电荷，您还添加了额外的电子，整个事物都是中性的
nuclear charge you also add an extra
electron the whole thing is neutral the
电子进入导带但你留在正核中
electron goes off into the conduction
band but you left in a positive nuclear
后面也要充电，所以这里的一切都是电中性的，没有电
charge behind as well so everything here
is electrically neutral no electric
场电子负电荷由核正补偿。
fields electron negative charge is
compensated by the nuclear positive
电荷，整个正电荷由受体补偿
charge and the whole positive charge is
compensated by the by the acceptor
到目前为止这里的负电荷很好，现在这里我们有电子在这里
negative charge here so far so good okay
now here we have electrons up here in
导带我们在价带上有孔，实际上
the conduction band and we have holes
here in the valence band and in fact
这个电子，如果他跌落到价带消灭它的空穴，他
this electron if he falls down to the
valence band annihilating its hole he
可以释放能量，例如可以发出光子并降低能量，那么
can let off energy he can emit a photon
for example and lower the energy so what
发生的是将电子重置这里的眼睛有点种族的转变
happens is reset the electron here an
eye a little bit of a race to transform
消灭整个电子消灭整个电子
annihilates the whole electron
annihilates the whole and you end up
对我来说是一个区域，在这里歼灭一次，然后歼灭
with a region to me annihilate one more
here annihilate one more and we end up
从这里到这里中间是这个区域，称为耗尽
with this region in the middle from here
to here which is known as the depletion
没有电子也没有电子的区域耗尽区
region depletion region
where there are no electrons and no
漏洞，没有移动电荷载体了
holes there's no mobile charge carriers
anymore
你只剩下静核电荷，没事了，所以你
you only have the static nuclear charges
left okay nothing moving around so you
可能认为这种this灭会继续下去，因为电子上升了
might think that this annihilation would
keep going because the electrons are up
在高能量时，空穴在低能量时下降，所以我们可以保持
at high energy and the holes are down at
low energy so we can just keep
消灭带有空穴的电子会继续发射光子，并且越来越低，
annihilating electrons with holes keep
emitting photons and lower and lower and
降低能量，但事实并非如此，它不会一直持续下去，
lower the energy but that's not true in
fact it doesn't keep going and the
之所以不能持续下去，是因为我们在这之后留下了净费用
reason it doesn't keep going is because
we're leaving a net charge behind this
该区域现在被充电，这是由于掺杂剂导致的净正电荷
region now is charged this is net
positive charge because of the dopants
这是净负电荷-电荷，所以当我们开始清醒时，我们离开
and this is net negative charge - charge
so as we start an eye elating we leave
实际上这里是带电区域，这里是带电区域，这意味着我们
actually a charged region here and a
charged region here and that means we
有一个电场，我想
have an electric field
I guess the electric field points from
-对正数和-存入正数负数让我们看看
the - to the positive and - deposit
positive negative which way let's see
那些正电荷的方向
the direction of a positive charge those
指向这种方式，电场从正网
points this way yeah
electric field goes from positive net
测试费用转为负数是的，没错，所以有一个
test charge goes towards the negative
yes okay got it right so so there's an
我们在这里建立的电场，随着我们的歼灭更多
electric field here that we're building
up and as we annihilate more more
电荷在这里最终会导致越来越多的电场，这意味着如果我们
charges here we end up with more and
more electric field and that means if we
要在这里再吸收一个电子，然后再消灭一个空穴，我们首先
want to take one more electron here and
annihilate one more hole here we first
我们必须要爬上一个潜在的山丘才能得到一个静电的山丘
must we must climb up a potential hill
an electrostatic potential hill to get
越过这个电场到达此处的某个孔
past this electric field to reach the
hole here at some point this
静电势山变得太大，我们无法克服它，我们
electrostatic potential hill becomes too
big and we can't get over it and we
不能再有an灭了，所以耗尽宽度耗尽了
can't have any more annihilation so the
depletion width deplete the depletion
宽度宽度通过设置间隙能量e间隙能量的数量来设置
width metion width is set by setting the
gap energy e gap the amount of energy
你会通过消除更多的能量和更多的电子而获得收益
you would you would gain by annihilating
one more energy with one more electron
Munroe孔的能量等于e乘以Delta Phi的能量
with Munroe hole is has to equal to e
times Delta Phi the amount of energy you
必须放入其中以使电子越过静电山
have to put into it to get the electron
over the electrostatic hill that you're
为使电子越过
fighting against to move the electron
past the
这个充电区域是清楚的，大概有人，是，好，至少有人
this charge region is that clear roughly
someone yes okay good at least someone
说是的，这里的这种潜力只是来自
said yes so and this this potential here
is just the integral of e dot DL from
整个系统都很好，所以通常我们不相信
well across the system alright so so the
generally we we don't believe that this
耗尽宽度将无限大，它将停止在
depletion width is going to be
infinitely big it's going to stop at
某些区域，但这不是绘制发生情况的好方法，因为这看起来
some region but this is not a good way
to draw what goes on because this looks
有点看起来有点奇怪，看起来看起来不正确，我的意思是看起来
a little it looks a little strange it
looks it looks incorrect I mean it looks
就像这里的电子具有较高的能量，而空穴具有较低的能量
like the electron here is at higher
energy and the hole is at lower energy
所以看起来电子仍然应该消灭空穴
so it kind of looks like the electron
should still want to annihilate the hole
但是我们知道有一个电场使它变得困难，所以我们
but we know that there's an electric
field that's making it difficult so we
我们想要做的是我们想要以某种方式重绘这张图片
what we want to do is we want to redraw
this picture in a way that will make it
很明显，电子不想来消灭另外一个空穴，所以
obvious that the electron doesn't want
to come and annihilate one more hole so
我们要做的是根据所谓的电化学势绘制事物
what we do is we draw things in terms of
the so-called electrochemical potential
电化学势是有规律的组合
electrochemical potential potential
which is the combination of the regular
化学势和静电势都可以，所以我们要作图
chemical potential and the electrostatic
potential okay so we're going to plot
相反，它将结合在一起，所以带结构
that instead which is going to combine
together the so the band structure
以及我们留下的空间电荷的库仑效应
diagram as well as the Coulomb effects
of the space charge that we left behind
所以在这边画一幅我们以前画过的画
so over on this side
draw the same picture we had before so
我们在这里有一个导电带电化学势
we have a the conduction band of energy
up here the electrochemical potential
我们将其放在此处，这是一个mu减去E Phi，我们有价带
we'll put here so this is a mu minus E
Phi over here we have the valence band
这边的能量D价现在在另一边，我们要排队
energy over here D valence now over here
on the other side we are going to line
电化学势完全相同，但是这里的价带
up the electrochemical potential exactly
the same but here the valence band
能量将是化合价，导带能量将在此处
energy will be here a valence and the
conduction band energy will be up here
传导和这些被连接在一起，就像这样，那是
the conduction and these get connected
together like this okay that's those are
应该是平行线不是很平行应该证明是的，让我
supposed to be parallel lines not very
parallel should prove it yeah let me
改善它需要更多一点，所以它们看起来非常隐约
improve it needs this up a little bit
more so they look very vaguely parallel
所以这些应该是我会教其他好的东西，所以我已经
so these are supposed to be
I'll teach other okay good so all I've
完成就是我把那张照片拍到那里，我把它扭曲了
done is I've taking that picture up
there and I've twisted it I've sort of
弯曲它以解决额外的静电势
bent it so as to account for the
additional electrostatic potential so
现在，在左侧和右侧，电化学势与
now that on the left and the right the
electrochemical potential lines up with
那里的电化学势，告诉我们的是那里
the electrochemical potential over here
and what that tells us is it that there
如果将电子从该侧移到该侧，则没有净驱动力
is no net driving force for moving an
electron from this side to this side if
化学势有变化，但化学势也有变化
there's a change in the chemical
potential but there's equal change in
补偿它的静电势，所以左侧和
the electrostatic potential that
compensates it so the left-hand side and
就电子而言，右侧完全对齐
the right-hand side are completely lined
up as far as the electron is concerned
它不想向左移动电子不想向左移动
it doesn't want to move to the left the
electron doesn't want to go to left
不想走到右边，它只是想说保持原状，所以这是
don't want to go to the right either it
just wants to say stay put so this is
平衡的情况是很清楚如何画出来的
the equilibrium situation is that sort
of clear how this has been drawn okay
好吧，那是一张可怕的照片，不是吗，但是这个设备在这里
all right that's a terrible picture
isn't it okay but this this device here
这基本上是PN结的物理原理，即使它像
this is basically the physics of the PN
Junction and even as it stands just like
没有做任何进一步的事情，这是一个有趣的设备，因为它
that without doing anything further it's
an interesting device because it's
基本上是太阳能电池太阳能电池或光电电池光电电池
basically a solar cell a solar or
photoelectric cell photoelectric cell
电池，其想法是将光子放入光子中
cell and the idea of this is that you
put in photons put in photons get out
当前得到电流，这种把光子放进去的想法
current get current and this idea of
putting in photons and getting our
当前是一个您知道的200亿美元的行业，如果人们
current is a you know twenty billion
dollar industry right now if people
试图建立光电池来替代我们的化石燃料，
trying to build photo cells that are
going to replace our fossil fuels and
可能拯救我们的世界免受全球变暖和其他一切的影响，所以我
potentially save our world from global
warming and everything else so I
鼓励大家进入半导体行业并尝试图
encourage all of you to go into the
semiconductor industry and try to figure
展示了我们将如何使太阳能电池更高效，以便我们能够获得所有
out how we're going to make solar cells
more efficient so that we can get all of
我们的力量来自这些东西，而不是燃烧煤炭，石油和其他东西
our power from these things instead of
from burning coal and oil and things
无论如何，让我们尝试弄清楚为什么这是该设备
like that at any rate let's try to
figure out why it is that this device
具有此属性，如果您将其置于灯光中，将会获得最新电流，因此，如果您
has this property that if you put in
light you'll get out current so if you
将光放入此图片中，您可以激发电子
put in light into this into this picture
you can excite an electron from the
价带至导带，所以您在后面留下一个洞
valence band up to the conduction band
so you leave a hole behind and you
从价态激发电子直至导带
excite an electron up to the conduction
band from the valence
现在在这个耗尽区，有一个电场，
and now in this depletion region there's
an electric field there's a strong
在此耗尽区中的电场，您可以在这张图片中通过
electric field in this depletion region
you can see it in this picture by the
这些带的曲率以及电子要发生什么
curvature of these bands and what
happens is the electron wants to it's
被电场朝这个方向推动，因为它想下降到
pushed by the electric field in this
direction because it wants to go down to
较低的能量，孔朝这个方向被推动，希望上升到更高
lower energy and the hole is pushed in
this direction wants to go up to higher
能量，因为空穴总是试图在能带结构中上升
energy because holes always try to go up
in the in the band structure and either
这样，这总是当前的趋势，它要么是积极的，要么是积极的
way this is always current
going to the right it's either positive
当前正电荷向右移动，这就是正向移动或
current positive charge going to the
right this is plus going to the right or
负电荷向左移动，这两个电流在同一电流中
negative charge going to the left and
both of those are current in the same
方向，因此只需在此处放置一个光子
direction so just by putting in a photon
here photon which creates this
激发你设法产生电流，所以这是你所知道的物理
excitation you manage to create current
so this is the you know the the physics
这将使我们免于全球变暖的影响之一，所以请您知道
is going to save us from global warming
one of these days so please you know go
进入这个世界，弄清楚如何更好地打造那些你知道他们是
off into the world and figure out how to
build those better you know they're
仍然不如燃烧化石燃料便宜，所以人们不愿意
still not quite as cheap as burning
fossil fuels so people aren't willing to
使用它们，但也许有一天我们会好起来的，这不是费迪南德·布朗
use them yet but maybe someday we will
okay this is not what Ferdinand Brown
在1874年发现了他发现的东西就是同一台设备
discovered in 1874 what he discovered
was something very was the same device
但是他发现了这些东西产生的另一种影响
but but he discovered another effect
that these things have which is maybe
同样有趣的是整改的效果，这意味着
equally interesting which is the effect
of rectification which means that
电流以一种方式流向Lowe一种方式，但另一种则不
current flows one way Lowe's one way one
way but not the other
如果您的电路很好，那么您也许可以弄清楚为什么
and if you're good with your circuits
you might be able to figure out why it
是具有此属性的东西，它可以纠正您
is that having something that with this
property which rectifies enables you to
建立一个收音机，这是他很快意识到的，如果您有东西
build a radio which is what he realized
very quickly that if you have something
纠正允许电流以一种方式流动，但不允许另一种方式流动
that rectifies allowing current to flow
one way but not the other
你可以用它来建立一个收音机，为什么呢？为什么呢？
you can build a radio with it so why is
why is this why does it have that
物理，好吧，让我们拿起这个装置，让我们想象一下，让我画
physics oh okay let's take this device
and let's imagine well let me draw the
再次显示相同的图片，除了我现在要做的是要输入电压
same picture again except what I'm going
to do now is I'm going to put a voltage
跨过这张图片以尝试使电流流动，所以让我们这样做
across this picture to try to get
current to flow so let's do that
绘制所有完全相同的图片您看到的是电化学势
draw all exactly the same picture you
see here's the electrochemical potential
mu减去e Phi在左边，然后在下面是价带能量
mu minus e Phi on the left and then down
here is the valence band energy availing
在这里，而不是准确地排列电化学势
over here instead of lining up the
electrochemical potentials exactly on
左右，我将把化学势转移到
the left and the right I'm going to
shift the chemical potential down to the
此处的电化学势，如果这是精确排列的
electrochemical potential down here so
this is if it was lined up exactly it
在这里排列完全相同，现在我将其向下移动
would be exactly the same lined up here
and now I'm going to shift it downwards
通过一些能量在这里传达出来，这就是
by evey here by some energy so this is
the electrochemical potential on the
现在就这样，因为我要在整个事情上施加电压
right so now because I'm putting a
voltage across the whole thing
所以我们必须在这里加上价带能量
so then we have to put in the valence
band energy I guess mu minus D Phi here
在这里，价带能量在这里是价和导带
is here and the valence band energy is
here a valence and the conduction band
能量将在此处感应，然后在耗尽区域中您有电
energy will be up here duction then in
the depletion region you have electric
像这样将这些连接在一起的字段，这样很清楚我画了什么
field which connects these together like
that okay so is it clear what I've drawn
在这里，我拍摄的照片完全相同，只是在
here I've taken exactly the same picture
I've just applied a voltage across the
两个将这种化学势转移到这里好吧，所以现在
two to shift this chemical potential
down to here good alright so um now now
我已经施加了这个电压有多少电流流过
that I've applied this this voltage how
much current flows well there's several
获得电流的方法一种获得电流的方法我们称此过程为
ways you can get current one way to get
current let's call this process one is
价带中的电子可以被激发到导带
that electron in the valence band could
get excited up to the conduction band
然后最终找到下坡路
and then eventually find its way down
the hill
好吧，让我们称过程1和过程2有点相反
okay so let's call that process one
and process 2 is sort of the reverse of
导带上的空穴会被激发下来
that which is the hole up in the
conduction band could get excited down
进入价带，因为记住需要正能量来推动一个洞
into the valence band because remember
requires positive energy to push a hole
下降到价带，然后找到它的上山路，所以过程1＆2 1＆
down into the valence band and then find
its way up the hill so process 1 & 2 1 &
2这要么是电子向左移动，要么是空穴向右移动，
2 this either an electron going to the
left or a hole going to the right and
无论哪种方式，比率都是e到负beta e差距，因为限制步骤是
either way it's rate is e to the minus
beta e gap because the limiting step is
使电子上升到导带或使空穴下降
to get the electron up into the
conduction band or get the hole down
进入价带，这会消耗您的能隙能量，所以它被激活了，所以
into the valence band and that costs you
the gap energy so it's activated okay so
这是可能会导致电流发生的一件事，而另一件事是
that's one thing that can happen that
can cause current but another thing that
如果您有一些电子，可能会导致电流
can happen that can cause current did
you have some number of electrons up
在导带中，他们可以爬上山，让我们
here in the conduction band already and
they could just climb up the hill let's
叫3或在价带上有一些孔，他们可以
call that 3 or we have some holes here
in the valence band and they can just
爬下山，我们称它为4，所以3＆4 3＆4我们有电子进入
climb down the hill let's call it 4 so 3
& 4 3 & 4 we have electrons going to the
右边或左边的孔，它们以e到负的比率发生
right or holes going to the left and
they happen at a rate of e to the minus
e gap-Evi为什么从这里到这里的这座山的高度这么好
e gap - Evi why is that well the height
of this hill from here to here is e gap
-Evi如果我们未应用此Evie，则间隙能量将完全相同
- Evi if we had not applied this evie it
would be exactly the same gap energy
我们需要爬上山，但是现在我们减少了那座山，
that we would need to climb up the hill
but now we've reduced that hill we
通过在系统上施加电压来减小山丘的大小
reduced the size of the hill by evey by
applying the voltage across the system
因此，当前的总JJ等于，这将是
so the total current total J J equals
well it's going to be a combination of
这两个东西，他们称其为1-e减去beta e差距减去3 4
these two things they call it a 1 - e to
the minus beta e gap minus a 3 4 those
只是负e差距的系数e-CD
are just coefficients e to the minus
beta e gap - CD which
好的，那么我们需要知道这些系数是多少，但实际上是
okay then we need to know what these
coefficients are but actually the sort
诀窍在于，电压为零时的电流应为零
of a trick for that that the current
when they're zero voltage should be zero
如果您不对系统施加任何电压，则不应获得任何电流，因此
if you don't apply any voltage to the
system you shouldn't get any current so
这意味着1 2和3 4应该相等，所以J与e成正比
that means a 1 2 and a 3 4 should be
equal so J is proportional to e to the
减去beta egapp，我认为乘以KBT的时间是EV
minus beta egapp I factored that out
times e to the e v over KBT
那是beta e V减去1 ok，所以这就是所谓的二极管方程二极管
that's beta e V minus 1 ok so this is
what's known as the diode equation diode
等式PN结或整流器有时也称为二极管
equation the PN Junction or the
rectifier is sometimes known as a diode
我们可以在此处绘制其行为，以便在该轴上有当前电压
and we can plot its behavior here so we
have current voltage on this axis and
该轴上的电流，它是电压的指数，所以这是
current on this axis and it's
exponential in in the voltage so this is
这是零电流，这是负电流，所以也许我应该
this is zero current here and this is
negative current here so maybe I should
画的像是零在这里，负在这里，所以正
have drawn it like this zero is here and
negative is here so it with positive
电压呈指数上升，而负电压呈恒定
voltage it goes up exponentially whereas
negative voltage it goes to a constant
这是一个非常小的常数，因此通常用图形表示
which is extremely small constant so
this is frequently drawn figuratively as
像这样笔直向上，像这样笔直平坦
being straight up like this and straight
flat like this which you know the
大概说它允许电流沿一个方向流动，并且不允许
approximately say it allows current to
flow in one direction and allows no
我们经常在另一个方向上流动电流
current to flow in the other direction
frequently we draw in a circuit diagram
我们画了一个像这样的二极管，这意味着电流仅流入一个
we draw a diode like this diode which
means current flows only in one
方向好吧，这是一种非常整洁的设备，可以在您进入电路时
direction okay it's pretty neat device
to put into your circuits when you're
设计电路，这就是费尔南德·布朗通过实验发现的
designing circuits so this was what
Fernand Brown discovered experimentally
或多或少，直到1940年代人们才真正了解
more or less and it wasn't understood
until 1940s when people really developed
对半导体物理学有很好的了解，那时他们
a good understanding of semiconductor
physics and by that time when they
终于了解了半导体物理学，他们意识到自己可以做得更多
finally understood semiconductor physics
they realize they could do a lot more
而不是仅仅制造二极管，这使他们能够启动
with it than just building diodes and
this enabled them to start
致力于改变世界的下一个重大发明
working on the next big invention that
changed the world which is the
晶体管由John Bardeen Walter的Bell Labs团队于1947年发明
transistor invented in 1947 by the Bell
Labs team of John Bardeen Walter
Brattain和William Shockley Bardeen绝对是每个人都应该使用的名字
Brattain and William Shockley Bardeen is
definitely a name that everyone should
知道是因为他知道晶体管的两个诺贝尔奖，一个因为晶体管
know because he one knew two Nobel
Prizes one for the transistor one for
超导理论是非常光明的，但几乎是未知的人
the theory of superconductivity are very
bright but pretty much unknown person
而该器件的晶体管是最基本的最小片
and this device the transistor is the
elementary the the smallest piece the
基本部件现在已经成为每台计算机制造的基础
elementary piece the building block of
every computer ever made now it's in
您的平均手机，笔记本电脑或iPad有数十亿个
your average cell phone or laptop or
iPad there are billions of these
数以十亿计的晶体管在那里
transistors sitting literally billions
of them in there
基本开关或基本放大器可以使所有功能
it's the elementary switch or elementary
amplifier that enables everything to
工作，所以晶体管有许多不同的品种，我们要去的品种
work so transistors come in many
different varieties the one we're going
要讨论的实际上是MOSFET MOSFET，它代表金属
to discuss is actually known as the
MOSFET MOSFET which stands for metal
氧化物氧化物半导体场效应晶体管电阻，我来解释
oxide oxide semiconductor field effect
transistor resistor and I'll explain
这是什么意思，尽管我们应该评论一下
what that means as we as we get to it
although I should comment that the
他们在1947年建造的原始晶体管不是这种设计，而是
original transistor that they built in
1947 was not of this design they were
意识到他们可以构建此设计，但由于各种原因，他们决定
aware that they could build this design
but for various reasons they decided
那不是他们要首先尝试建造的那个。
that was not the one they were going to
try to build first this is the type of
现在最常在电路中使用的晶体管，这就是为什么要解释
transistor that's used most frequently
in circuits now so that's why explaining
那个也更容易理解它使谈论方式变得更好
that one it's also easier to understand
it makes it nicer to talk about the way
它的工作原理是相当简单的设备，需要大量的半导体，
it works is fairly simple device you
take a big piece of semiconductor and
你P掺杂它，它有这样的表面，你可以向后做
you P dope it and it has a surface like
this you could do it backwards you could
内在，但如果您想，但让我们开始想象它是P掺杂的，那么我们采取
endo but if you wanted to but let's
start imagine it's P doped then we take
两个小区域，最后我们把它们扩大到了这个区域
two small regions and we end up them
make it a little bigger this region here
n在这里掺杂这个区域，然后我们在这里掺杂这个区域，这是
n doped this region here and then we'll
M dope this region here this and this is
所有P掺杂都可以，所以我们现在拥有的表面是N掺杂n掺杂
all P doped okay so what we have now is
we have a surface with an N dope n dope
还有大量的P掺杂，我们将在此处放置联系人
and a big bulk with P doped we'll put
contacts here on
电线进入我们称为源极-源极线，这被称为漏极
wires coming in this we call a source
source wire and this is called the drain
线漏，然后我们尝试现在将电流从源极流到漏极
wire drain and then we try to run
current from the source to the drain now
如果您在这里查看此结构，您将意识到它不是当前的
if you look at this structure here
you'll realize that it's current is not
从源头流到漏极
going to flow from the source to the
drain
您会在nmp之间的界面处有一个耗尽区，有一个NP
you'll have a depletion region at the
interface between nmp there's an NP
那里的结和PN结在这里，其中一个PN结想要
Junction there and PN Junction here and
one of the PN junctions wants the
当前只以一种方式流动，而另一种只希望其流动
current to only flow one way and the
other one wants it to flow only the
另一种方式，你可以比喻地想像一下，因为你知道两个
other way you can kind of think of it
figuratively as being you know two
背对背二极管指向相反的方向，因此其中一个仅允许
back-to-back diodes pointing in opposite
directions so one of them only allows
流到左边的电流只有另一个是流过的电流
the current to flow to the left the
other one only was the current to flow
在右边，所以在他们两个之间您无法通过
to the right so between the two of them
you can't get any kind of through it at
一切都好，所以这看起来很无聊，但是现在我们添加了
all okay so this looks like a boring
device but now we add the last part of
这样的设备，我们在上面放了一块大金属
the device we put a big piece of metal
on top like this
被称为金属金属门的门，然后我们将其连接到
which is known as the gate that metal
metal gate and then we attach it to the
通过一点点电池来供电，所以电压加上类似的电池
source via a little bit of battery here
so voltage plus battery like that
附在金属栅极上，然后我们在两者之间放置一个绝缘体
attached to the metal gate and then we
put an insulator in between here which
通常是氧化物层，这就是设备金属的名称
is usually an oxide layer and this is
what gives the name of the device metal
氧化物半导体，因此门是金属，氧化物在中间，
oxide semiconductor so the gate is metal
the oxide is in the middle and the
底部的半导体氧化物的目的只是为了制造一个小的
semiconductors on the bottom the purpose
of the oxide is just to make a small
绝缘层，这样金属就不会接触半导体了
insulating layer so the metal doesn't
touch the semiconductor you can make it
任何您想要的东西通常都是由氧化物制成，非常好
of anything you want it's just typically
made of oxides which are very nice
绝缘子，它们很容易制造，您可以用任何绝缘子制成
insulators and they're easy to build you
could make it of any insulator you
想放在那里，你可以使它成为Dimond，你可以使它成为你知道的
wanted to put there you could make it of
Dimond you can make it of you know it
如果您愿意的话，可能只是真空，但关键是您必须拥有金属
could be just vacuum if you wanted but
the point is you have to have the metal
不接触半导体，因此通常称为金属氧化物半导体
not touching the semiconductor so it's
usually called metal oxide semiconductor
实际上，闸门不必一定是金属，也不必一定是金属
in fact the gate doesn't have to be
metal either it just has to be
因此，只要在任何地方进行，它就可以随心所欲
conducting so it can be whatever you
want as long as it's conducting at any
之所以称其为金属氧化物半导体，是因为它几乎总是
rate it's called metal oxide
semiconductor because it's almost always
由金属氧化物和半导体制成的，这的目的是什么
made of metal oxide and semiconductor
all right so what's the purpose of this
金属化这个金属门，您可以对其充电，因此它上面有正电荷
metal this metal gate you charge it up
so it has plus charges on it and this
加上电荷就像一个电容器，它们将吸引负数
plus charges act like a capacitor and
they're going to attract negative
在这里的半导体上充电现在这个区域是一些
charges on the semiconductor here now
this region is some
因此，如果您基本上只是在金属和
so if you basically just charging up a
capacitor plate between the metal and
半导体这个区域，它位于过去用于半导体的顶部
the semiconductor this region here on
the top of the semiconductor it used to
被p掺杂时您会在那里刺孔，但现在我们吸引了很多
be p-doped you stab holes there
but now we've attracted a lot of
电子进入该区域，因此不再是P掺杂，而是主要是n掺杂
electrons into that region so instead of
being P doped it's now majorly n dope
因为我们知道你只是在那儿吸引了电子，所以现在是n
because we've you know we just attracted
electrons there so now it's n so instead
像我最初拥有的那张照片现在看起来
of having something that looks like that
picture I had originally it now looks
更像是从这里到这里的整个区域
more like this this whole region here
all the way from here to here is
负的是n掺杂的n中有电子，并且耗尽区
negative is n is n doped has has
electrons in it and the depletion region
有点像这样的大环境现在您可以在这里获得最新的
sort of makes a big sort of environment
like this now here you can get current
通过该电子通道直接从该末端区域到该末端区域
directly from this end region to this
end region by this electron channel so
您已经在该层中添加了电子，以便电子可以直接从
you've added electrons to this layer so
the electrons can travel directly from
源极到漏极而不必经过PN结
the source to the drain without having
to go through a PN Junction that's the
好吧，就是对那个好东西感到满意，所以
point okay is that good happy with that
alright good so the characteristics of
这样的设备看起来或多或少像这样，如果您绘制电流与
such a device look more or less like
this that if you plot the current versus
电压这是源极和漏极之间的电压这是
the voltage this is the voltage between
the source and the drain this is the
如果不施加栅极电压，则电流将从源极流到漏极
current that flows from the source to
the drain if you put no gate voltage on
门等于零，几乎没有电流流动，但是如果你放一点
the gate equals zero you get almost no
current flowing but if you put a little
栅极上的栅极电压位等于2伏特等于2伏特
bit of gate voltage on the gate equals
say two volts equals two volts you all
突然之间有很多商店都在消耗电流，所以这使您可以
of a sudden get a lot of stores drain
current so this enables you to take the
栅极上的小电压并控制很大的电流，所以这基本上是
small voltage on the gate and control a
very large current so this is basically
您知道为什么该设备如此有用以至于可以充当放大器的原因
you know the why this device is so
useful it acts as an amplifier it can
放大门上很小的信号，然后您就可以做一些有趣的事情
amplify a very small signal on the gate
and then you can do interesting things
有了它，因为现在它已经成为一大潮流，您可以使用
with it because now it's become a big
current that you can work with okay the
构成现代所有计算机的基本电路
elementary circuit that element that
builds all computers in the modern age
好的，我希望你们中的许多人会继续学习更多的半导体
all right well I hope many of you will
go on and study more semiconductor
设备物理过程比过去的35分钟还要多，但这就是我们所需要的时间
device physics more than these last 35
minutes but this is all we have time for
不幸的是，在此过程中，我们必须继续进行最后阶段
in this course unfortunately we have to
move on to the the final segment of our
当然，我们课程的最后一部分是
course the final segment of our course
is to
把所有这些东西抛在我们后面，我们继续研究磁性
leaving all this stuff behind us and we
move on to study magnetism magnetism so
深吸一口气，然后我们继续讲磁性，第一个问题是
可能想问的是，为什么我们要研究磁性？为什么呢？
probably wants to ask is is why are we
studying magnetism and why are you
从第一天开始，现在就学习磁性的整个过程
studying magnetism now the whole course
pretty much from day one all the way up
在中途讲课十八次，现在我们真的
to lecture eighteen halfway through
which is right now we've really been
一种或另一种方式研究波浪和固体的振动波
studying waves and solids one way or the
other way their vibrational waves over
那里的电子波或X射线波我们实际上只是在研究波
there electron waves or the x-ray waves
we're really just been studying waves in
固体以一种或另一种方式存在，并且磁性有些不同
solids in one way or the other
and magnetism is a little bit different
当我们开始磁性时，我们并不是真正在研究波浪和固体，所以为什么
we're not really studying waves and
solids when we starting magnetism so why
是我们对磁性的研究很好吗，我们有很多原因想要
is it that we're studying magnetism well
there's a lot of reasons why we want to
研究磁性我们想研究磁性的第一个原因是
study magnetism the first reason why we
want to study magnetism is it certainly
自古以来就知道这种效果，因为您知道它们是记录
it's an effect that's been known about
since antiquity you know they're records
知道磁力的人们，在希腊1000 BC，在中国1000 BC，
of people knowing about magnetism 1000
BC in Greece thousand BC in China they
知道如何制作指南针，它可能早于成千上万
knew how to build compasses and it
probably predates that by thousands of
多年以来，他们可能是穴居人，他们知道磁性被卡住了
years probably they were cavemen who
knew about magnetism you're stuck notes
无论如何冰箱上都非常严重，但尽管事实是
on the refrigerator so serious anyway
but but despite the fact that this
众所周知，您知道成千上万年前
effect was was known about you know
thousands and thousands years ago there
直到人们明白了，它才完全不了解它
was absolutely no understanding of it
whatsoever until people understood
量子力学，这实际上使这一点非常有趣
quantum mechanics and that's one thing
that makes this very interesting in fact
Bohr和Van Leeuwen有一个定理，称为Bohr Van Leeuwen
there's a theorem by Bohr and Van
Leeuwen known as the Bohr Van Leeuwen
定理Niels Bohr我想大家都知道，但是henryka Van Leeuwen是其中之一
theorem Niels Bohr I think everyone
knows but henryka Van Leeuwen was one of
他的学生Lewin定理和摩拉维亚Lewin定理的内容是
his students Lewin theorem and the
content of the moravian Lewin theorem is
没有量子和，基本上没有磁性，没有量子，但是没有
basically no magnetism without quantum
sum without quantum but nothing in
古典物理学可以在任何意义上给您带来磁性，所以
classical physics can ever give you
magnetism in any sense so that's kind of
一个有趣的陈述，它告诉我们您知道磁场是一种
an interesting statement so it tells us
that you know that magnetism is a really
去了解你的宏观后果的好地方
good place to go to understand you know
the macroscopic ramifications of
微观磁性，这就是您要研究它的原因之一
microscopic magnetism so that's one of
the reasons why you want to study it
我们要研究磁性的另一个原因是，
another reason we want to study
magnetism is because it's a rather
我们一直在做的一切都失败了
spectacular
failure of everything we've been doing
到目前为止，磁性我们迄今为止一直在研究的带理论将始终
so far that magnetism the band theory
we've been studying so far would always
预测您具有与向下自旋电子相同数量的向上自旋电子
predict that you have the same number of
up spin electrons as down spin electrons
而在磁场中，事实并非如此，因为您在其中有磁性物质
whereas in magnetism it's just not true
you have magnetic substances where you
具有不同数量的自旋电子和自旋电子
have a different number of spin up
electrons and spin down electrons it's
完全超出了乐队理论，而且完全没有预料到
completely outside of band theory and
it's completely not predicted so
磁性是一种理解我们已经存在的局限性的方法
magnetism is a way to understand with
the limitations of what we've already
一直在做的最后原因可能不是那么明显，就是磁性
been doing the final reason which is
maybe not so obvious is that magnetism
是研究物质各相之间相变的好地方，因此
is a really great place to study phase
transitions between phases of matter so
每个人都熟悉您在冰和水之间的相变或
everyone's familiar with your phase
transitions between ice and water or
水和蒸汽，您可能已经在热力学中研究了这些东西
water and steam and you probably studied
these things in your thermodynamics
上课，但是当真正开始了解这些阶段的细节时
classes but when one really gets down to
understanding the details of these phase
我们对相变了解的大部分来自研究
transitions most of what we know about
phase transitions comes from studying
磁铁，可以更好地控制和更好地理解事物
magnets where things are much better
controlled and much better understood
关于冰融化成水的许多知识，我们实际上
and much of what we know about the
melting of ice into water we actually
知道，因为我们研究了磁铁，然后将知识转化为您
know because we studied magnets and then
we so translated our knowledge into you
知道对冰和水的了解不是显而易见的，我们将做出
know understanding ice and water that's
not an obvious statement we will make
如果您继续学习，则对本课程中的相变有一些陈述
some statements about phase transitions
in this course if you go on to study
其他课程，您将学到很多有关的知识，所以让我们先定义一下
other courses you'll learn a lot more
about it okay so let's start by defining
两种类型的磁性我们将要工作的磁性类型
a couple of types of magnetism types of
magnetism that we're going to be working
或至少一些我们需要的磁性类型
on of magnetism or at least some of the
types of magnetism we're going to need
要知道通常我们要做的是对某个物体施加磁场
to know about usually what we do is we
apply a magnetic field to some object
我们测量oops，我们测量磁化强度M，并且有一个比例
and we measure oops we measure a
magnetization M and there's a proportion
如果存在比例常数，我们称比例为Chi
that if there's a proportionality
constant we call the proportionality Chi
零零散散的地方，气被称为磁化率或磁化
over mu naught where Chi is known as the
susceptibility or magnetic
易感性我要拼写错误的USC Sept能力Sept能力
susceptibility I'm going to spell that
wrong s USC Sept ability Sept ability
零磁通是通常的磁导率
and nu naught is the usual magnetic
permeability the thing that's
渗透数据表上的东西
permeability
the thing that's on your datasheet and
您的考试是这样定义的，有两种磁性
your exams so given that as a definition
there's a couple kinds of magnetism that
你可以有一个是功率磁，这意味着或功率磁是任何
you can have one is power magnetism
which means or power magnet is any
chi大于零的材料，换句话说，您施加了磁场
material with chi greater than zero in
other words you apply a magnetic field
你会在与磁场相同的方向上获得磁矩
and you get a magnetic moment in the
same direction as the field that you
应用似乎似乎有一定道理，我们已经知道
applied which seems to make some amount
of sense and we have know a couple of
该示例示例的示例是自由旋转，可能在
examples of that example example one is
a free spin probably studied this in
去年的统计力学，如果您有自由旋转的机会，
statistical mechanics last year if you
have a free spin sort is sitting in
如果向外部空间施加磁场，则其能量会降低
outer space if you apply a magnetic
field to it its energy is lower if the
磁矩指向与磁场相同的方向，因此自旋
magnetic moment points in the same
direction as magnetic field so the spin
将尝试翻转并指向与磁场相同的方向，并且
will try to flip over and point in the
same direction as the magnetic field and
自由自旋是一个功率磁体，在前面我们研究过的第二个示例中
the free spin is a power magnet um
example two which we studied earlier in
这个术语是费米气体我们的电子气体我们应该研究Sommerfeld模型
this term is a Fermi gas our electron
gas we should study the Sommerfeld model
我们发现有一种称为多功率磁性的磁性
and we found known as poly power
magnetism our magnetism there was some
计算结果与之基本相同
calculation which went along with that
it's basically exactly the same physics
你有一束电子，你在瞬间施加磁场
you have a bunch of electrons you apply
magnetic field the moments of the
电子想要与磁场对准以降低能量，但是
electrons want to align with the
magnetic field to lower the energy but
由于保利（Pauli）排除原则，他们不能全部翻身，所以只有少数
they can't all flip over because of the
Pauli exclusion principle so only a few
他们翻转，但仍然发展出的磁化强度
of them flip over but nonetheless the
magnetization that develops is in the
与施加的磁场方向相同，所以这是一种力量
same direction as the magnetic field
that's been applied so this is a power
磁铁我会比自由旋转弱一点，因为只有一些
magnet I'll be at a weaker one than the
free spin because only some of the
在费米气体的情况下，电子将翻转。好吧，我们将详细介绍
electrons will flip over in the case of
a Fermi gas okay we'll say more about
不久之后，另一种常见的磁性是
those in a little while so another type
of magnetism which is common is
反磁性，基本上意味着Chi小于零，换句话说，
diamagnetism which basically means Chi
is less than zero in other words when
你施加磁场，磁矩想指向相反的方向
you apply magnetic field the magnetic
moment wants to point in the opposite
方向作为磁场现在我们可能不知道任何例子
direction as the magnetic field now we
may not know any examples of that
立即出现，但在质量上有相似之处
immediately but there's something that's
qualitatively similar
我们确实像伦茨定律一样定性地知道，您可能从第一年起就记得
we do know qualitatively like Lenz's law
which you may remember from first year
EMM镜片法则提醒您，如果使用磁性材料，则如果您有电线圈，
EMM lenses law to remind you if you have
a loop of wire if you apply a magnetic
导线回路的磁场将在该导线回路中流动，以与
field to the loop of wire currents will
flow in that loop of wire to oppose the
磁场，所以你在相反的方向发展磁矩
magnetic field so you're developing a
magnetic moment in the opposite
磁场变化的方向导线环不是
direction of the change in magnetic
field a loop of wire however is not a
磁铁的原因是因为你会产生一个磁矩
diamagnet the reason for this is because
that you'll develop a magnetic moment
但最终电流和电线将衰减并下降至零，
but eventually the current and the wire
will will decay and go down to zero and
您将不会在导线中留下任何磁性力矩，因此实际上它没有磁性
you'll have no magnetic moment left in
the wire so in fact it's not magnetic at
它没有磁矩，除非导线是没有导体的超导体
all it has no magnetic moment unless the
wire is a superconductor which has no
电阻电流永不衰减，电流将持续流动
resistance currents never decay and the
current would keep flowing around
永远，直到永远，而磁矩将永远留在那里
forever and ever and ever and and the
magnetic moment would stay there forever
而且那是一个真正的反磁铁，我们今年不研究超导体
and ever and that's a real diamagnet we
don't study superconductors this year
很高兴知道您可以用超导体做到这一点，
just nice to know that that you could do
this with a superconductor you can get a
无论如何，反磁物理学实际上是真正的垫子反磁铁
real mat diamagnet anyway that the
physics of diamagnetism is actually
在性质上与镜片定律非常相似，但是当您添加
quite similar qualitatively to the
physics of lenses law but when you add
您可以通过某种解释了解量子力学
quantum mechanics to it you kind of you
know in some interpretation you can
认为这些潮流永远被困在那儿并且总是在对立
think of these currents as being being
stuck there forever and always opposing
磁场，即使您知道何时会镜片定律
the magnetic field even when you you
know when you it would lenses law you
必须不断改变磁场以使电流持续流过
have to keep changing the magnetic field
to get the current to keep flowing in a
只要磁场保持在电流上，反磁铁就应
diamagnet as long as the magnetic field
stays on the current the current should
保持流动，所以我们会在第三种情况下看到这种情况
keep flowing so we'll see how that
happens in a bit okay the third case
我们需要知道的是铁磁体的情况
that we need to know about is the case
of a Ferro magnet which is when
即使B等于零，磁化强度也不等于零，例如
magnetization is not equal to zero
even when B equals zero something like
铁具有此属性粘在冰箱上的东西是
iron has this property the thing that
sticks to your refrigerator this is the
当我们想到磁铁时，我们通常认为它是磁铁
thing that we usually think of as a
magnet when we think about magnets so a
开始研究磁性的好地方是一次一个原子，因此我们将
good place to start our study of
magnetism is one atom at a time so we'll
从原子磁性开始，我们将建立
start with atomic magnetism
atomic magnetism and we'll build up to
真实材料的磁性，我应该知道吗？
magnetism of real materials and I should
you know put it in this caveat that we
我们总是会忽略无视原子核的磁性。
always will we will ignore ignore the
magnetism of nuclei nuclear nuclei all
在一起，而我们忽略原子核的原因是，如果您考虑
together and the reason why we ignore
the nuclei is that if you think about
玻尔磁子给定的某个物体的磁矩是两个M
the magnetic moment of some object it's
given by the Bohr Magneton we're two M
电子对象的数量，这大致取决于G因子，即
of the object for an electron this is
roughly the up to the G factor this is
电子的磁矩对于核子和质子，
the magnetic moment of an electron it's
similar for a nucleon and a proton or
中子，但进入这里的质量大千分之一或
neutron but the mass that enters in here
is bigger by a factor of a thousand or
两千左右，这样你从
two thousand or something so that the
magnetic moment that you get from a
原子核比你得到的磁矩小得多
nucleus is much much much much much
smaller than the magnetic moment you get
来自电子，这就是为什么我们通常不关心磁性的原因
from electrons and that's why we're
usually not concerned with the magnetism
原子核有时在那里很重要，特别是如果
of nuclei it is there it's sometimes
turns out to be important especially if
您正在考虑温度极低的事物，或者
you're thinking about things at
extremely low temperatures or if you're
看着非常微妙和出色的效果，您确实需要担心
looking at very very subtle and fine
effect you do have to worry about the
原子核的磁性，但对我们来说，我们只会担心
magnetism of nuclei but for us we're
only gonna be worried about about the
电子的磁性，因为它更大，所以我们要
magnetism of the electrons because it's
just much bigger okay so we're going to
忽略原子核，然后我们就必须以写法开始
ignore the nuclei and then we have to
start the way we always start by writing
用哈密顿量来表示原子中的电子，所以我写哈密顿量
down a Hamiltonian for the electrons in
the atom so I'll write the Hamiltonian
哈密​​顿量，对哈密顿量使用某种脚本H是常规做法
Hamiltonian and it's conventional to use
sort of a script H for the Hamiltonian
因此您不会将其与磁感应强度H混淆，您知道B和H
so you don't get it confused with a
magnetic induction H you know B and H
还有你和那种东西，所以我们用汉密尔顿字母H
and you and that kind of stuff so we use
a script H for the Hamiltonian and we'll
希望以您以前见过的方式写出来，所以有一个动力学术语P
write it in hopefully ways that you've
seen before so there's a kinetic term P
加上EA平方超过2m，其中a是矢量电势del交叉a是B
plus EA squared over 2m where a is the
vector potential del cross a is B
无论我决定对系统施加什么磁场，
whatever magnetic field I decide to
apply to the system then there's going
就是这样，这只是动能，那么将会有一个吸引力
to be so this is just the kinetic energy
then there's going to be an attraction
到R的核V和我们之前见过的最后一项
to the nucleus V of R and the last term
we've seen before
g ub b点sigma，这在um两端的术语上是相同的，也许一个
g ub b dot sigma and this is the same on
the term same on um two ends maybe one
结束有人知道结束语谢谢你，周一词是我的笔记我的笔记说我的
end anyone know what one end thank you
de mon term is my notes my notes say my
笔记不要说还可以，所以这个词告诉你
notes don't say it okay alright so this
is the term that tells you that the
如果电子指向电子的磁矩是较低的能量
magnetic moment of the electron is lower
energy if the electron points in the
如果磁矩指向相同方向，则方向相同
same direction if the magnetic moment
points in the same direction of magnetic
字段，这变得非常令人困惑，迹象变得非常令人困惑，请记住
field this gets very confusing the signs
get very confusing here remember that
电子自旋的磁矩指向与其相反的方向
the magnetic moment of an electron spin
points in the opposite direction of its
磁矩，因为电子上的电荷为负
magnetic moment because the charge on
the electron is negative okay
所以看起来这里的能量会更低
so it looks as if the energy would be
lower here when the so here here the
如果Sigma与B方向相反，则能量较低
energy is lower if Sigma is in the
opposite direction of B so it's pointing
方向相反，所以它是负数，但如果Sigma相反
in the opposite direction so it's
negative but if Sigma is in the opposite
方向是B磁矩实际上是Sigma的相反方向
direction is B the magnetic moment is
actually the opposite direction of Sigma
因此磁矩指向与BI知道减号的方向相同的方向
so the magnetic moment is pointing the
same direction as B I know minus signs
你知道我的死好吗B是电子的玻尔磁子
are you know the death of me okay mu B
is the Bohr Magneton for the electron
G是G因子，通常只需要2就可以了，怎么办
and G is the G factor which will usually
take to be just 2 all right so what do
我们做得很好，我们真的很想治疗磁场
we do with this well we're really would
like to treat the magnetic field a
如果可以的话，请稍作扰动，以便您知道我们将以
little bit as a perturbation if we could
so you know that we'll start by
用以下方式重写此哈密顿量H等于P平方2m
rewriting this Hamiltonian as in the
following way H equals P squared over 2m
加上R的V，即H 0或B的H等于0
plus V of R and that is just H 0 or H of
B equals zero separate out that term
首先，我们还有几句话还没写，所以也许
first then we have a couple terms left
over that we didn't write yet so maybe
让我们在这里写这些或所有这些东西，然后我们再写
let's write those here plus or plus all
this stuff then we're gonna write next
所以一个是向量电位为2m P点a加上点P的交叉项
so one is the cross term with the vector
potential a over 2m P dot a plus a dot P
还有一个术语，向量电势平方超过2m平方，
and then there's another term the vector
potential squared over 2m a squared and
那么我们在G UB上还有相同的期限
then we have the same on term left over
G UB
B点Sigma，然后我们需要在这里做一些工作，
B dot Sigma and then we have to do a
little bit of work here and one piece of
我们需要做的工作是我们需要简化这个术语以及我们的方式
work we need to do is we need to sort of
simplify this term and the way we're
要简化，那就是通过选择量规选择矢量量规
going to simplify that is by choosing a
gauge choose gauge for the vector
电位，而我要选择的量规是矢量电位
potential and the gauge I'm going to
choose is that the vector potential is
1/2 B十字R，如果您这样选择，确实可以让您十字A
1/2 B cross R and if you choose it like
that this this does give you del cross a
等于B，如果您这样选择，则A和P实际上通过
equals B if you choose it like this then
a and P actually commute through with
彼此，也许不是很明显看到这是真的，但这是真的
each other and it's maybe not so obvious
to see that that's true but it is true
因为a的X分量包含我们的y分量，所以X
because the X component of a contains
the y component of our so the X
计算的分量与P的X分量和交换。
component of a compute commutes with the
with the X component component of P and
这些是彼此相乘的，所以哪一个都没关系
those are the ones that are multiplied
by each other so it doesn't matter which
订购它们，以便选择此量规，然后我们可以将其改写为e
order you put them in so choosing this
gauge we can then rewrite this as e over
2 m到点P，所以这两个人彼此上下班，然后我们将
2 m to a dot P so those two commute
right through each other and then we'll
用表达式写出一口井，我们将用1/2抵消两个，得到B
write in our expression for a well we'll
cancel the two with the 1/2 and we get B
两端都标有P，我们使用三元产品标识将其重写为e
across are dotted with P we use a triple
product identity to rewrite that as e
超过2m b点R交叉PR交叉P，然后仅吸收H bar的因数
over 2m b dot R cross P R cross P and
then just absorbing a factor of H bar
进入R十字P将识别出该物体为角动量并放
into the R cross P will recognize this
thing as in the angular momentum and put
H棒在这里，所以我们得到mu B和B点L其中L是轨道角
the H bar up here so we get mu B and B
dot L where L is the orbital angular
动量等于轨道角动量
momentum equals orbital angular momentum
因此，将所有这些放在一起，最终得到最终的哈密顿量
so putting this all together we end up
with the final Hamiltonian that we're
要与哈密顿量一起工作的是哈密顿量，其V等于0加
going to work with the Hamiltonian is
the Hamiltonian at V equals 0 plus
几个项emuebie点缀着轨道角动量加G倍
couple terms emuebie be dotted with the
orbital angular momentum plus G times
自旋角动量再加上这一项，我们将d平方
the spin angular momentum Plus this one
more term that we're left out d squared
超过2m的平方，我想也许我们应该在那儿停下来，下次再取车
over 2m a squared and I guess maybe we
should stop there and pick up next time
用这个哈密顿量，我们将分析磁场对此的影响
with this Hamiltonian and we'll analyze
the effect of the magnetic field on this
哈密​​尔顿人好吧，明天见，别忘了开会
Hamiltonian okay see you tomorrow
don't forget the meetings meeting right
讲完P JCC之后，还有像今天下午在
after the lecture P JCC and then also
the hinds like you did this afternoon at
下午5点寻找太阳系外行星或
5 p.m.
searching for extrasolar planets or
好的再见[鼓掌]
something okay bye
[Applause]